Robert L. DiMauro Jr.

Address: 500 Broadway APT 5107 Malden, Massachusetts 02148 Phone: (207) 749-2300 • Email: robert.louis.dimauro@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced Provider Network Executive with the ability to negotiate and problem solve in an efficient and effective manner. Provider focused with a strong understanding of healthcare reimbursement methodologies, managed care policies, claims, interpretation and negotiation of complex provider contracts.

Education

University of Southern Maine Master's Degree in Health Policy and Management September 2008 – May 2011

University of Southern Maine Bachelor's Degree in Health Sciences September 2000 – May 2005

Experience

Provider Network Executive

Neighborhood Health Plan Inc. Boston, Massachusetts. 02210 July 2011 – Present

Responsibilities include:

- Currently managing 5 hospitals and 105 provider group contracts in northern Massachusetts.
- Negotiating provider contracts and case rates within my assigned network.
- Primary liaison to providers for interpreting or resolving hospital contract language and payment issues.
- Collaborating with the contracting department to resolve and reconfigure hospital contract discrepancies.
- Partnering with the contracting and finance departments to conduct financial analysis to identify, develop, and implement competitive reimbursement.
- Facilitating monthly meetings with complex hospital delivery systems and provider groups to resolve claims, enrollment, and reimbursement issues.
- Educating providers on current Medicare, Medicaid and Neighborhood Health Plan payment and policy guidelines.

Provider Relations Liaison

Aetna Inc.

South Portland, Maine. 04106 September 2007 – April 2011

Responsibilities included:

 Collaborated with contract managers to negotiate out of state case rates for emergency services.

- Partnered with the state contracting department to resolve out of state contract and case rate discrepancies.
- Developed and maintained strong relationships with physician and management staff of complex hospital delivery systems in the greater Boston area.
- Worked with state officials to resolve member and provider complaints affecting the Medicaid health plan.
- Acted as a provider liaison for the state government to resolve out of state claims, prior authorizations, credentialing, and enrollment issues.
- Helped support Medicaid care management programs by conducting health risk assessments and educating over 1,000 chronically ill Medicaid members annually.
- Resolved daily out of state prior authorization inquiries from providers and Medicaid members.

Skills

Communication/Interpersonal/Verbal

- Selected by senior management to present cross departmental functions and responsibilities of the Medicaid business unit to the chief executive officer of Aetna in 2009.
- Selected by the executive director to interpret and present the results from the annual Aetna employee satisfaction survey to the Medicaid business unit department.
- Presented a health policy paper on leadership to the presidents of Mercy Hospital and Maine Medical Center in 2010.

Problem-Solving/Analytical/Research

- Solved and collaborated with the contracting department to reconfigure and retract \$500,000 in over payments made to a complex hospital in my assigned network.
- Discovered and resolved a system error that was allowing explanation of benefits for certain claims to be displayed incorrectly for non-participating providers.
- Reconfigured and resolved an ongoing case rate issue that a complex hospital was having for over a year, resulting in cost savings of \$175,000.

Teamwork/Adaptability/Flexibility

- Collaborated with the contracting department to resolve physician fee schedule payment errors, resulting in cost savings of \$150,000.
- Helped design and complete a searchable provider database tool that improved efficiency by decreasing average call times by 10% in the care management department.
- Received the 2011 Neighborhood Health Plan team key contributor award for exceeding the company goal of 5,000 new registered online users within 6 months.

Activities

Aetna Wellness Ambassador: South Portland, Maine. June 2009 – December 2010

Aetna Volunteer Committee: South Portland, Maine. April 2009 – June 2010

Aetna Medicaid Employee Relations Committee: South Portland, Maine. May 2010 – December 2010